GREGG HUDSON

contact@dochudson.co.uk info.dochudson.co.uk
07971 042338

SUMMARY

In my current role, I have provided leadership in the delivery of one of the largest digital transformation programmes in UK policing history, taking personal ownership of the mobility and automation strategies, and providing significant contribution to the M365 programme, amongst others.

I have worked closely with partners across the various supply chains and promoted a "one team" philosophy which has ensured partner buy in and accelerated success with both technologies, resulting in widespread recognition demonstrated through a number of internationally received case studies, webinars and awards.

I am passionate about digital transformation with a particular interest in how delivering the right user experiences can facilitate the adoption of change in an enterprise. I have achieved this through the identification of available technologies and designing solutions that synergistically combine the best available products to maximise value and drive customer success.

My prior experience in academia has provided me with advance critical thinking, analytical and problem solving skills. All of which enable me to collate and digest information quickly and has enabled me to rapidly adapt and excel in the fast changing nature of enterprise IT.

A portfolio of case studies highlighting recent successes is available via the link provided above.

EMPLOYMENT

WEST MIDLANDS POLICE

Mobility & Automation Manager

Manager of the Mobility Competency Centre and Centre for Applied Automation

Birmingham/Remote June 2017 to Current

Mobility Competency Centre

- · Responsible for the Strategy, Governance and Delivery of the organisation's enterprise mobility solutions.
- Leading a team of technical specialists, analysts and requirements consultants to deliver MDM/EMM/UEM, mobile applications and devices to frontline police officers and supporting staff.
- Orchestrating a full architectural redesign and strategic shift to Android Enterprise alongside the implementation a User Experience focused strategy which saw an increase in both usage and adoption and was responsible for process changes recovering millions of wasted hours per year.
- · Personal responsibility and oversight of a multimillion annual budget and the associated contracts.
- Chairing of monthly meetings with customer and user representatives from executive to end-user in order to prioritise activities against organisational and local strategies to ensure continued success.
- Provided leadership and expertise on wide ranging projects including Command and Control & Crime Management System replacements and Microsoft 365 implementation.
- Delivered a sector first, Progressive Web Application in a secure, cloud-hosted environment to provide briefing material and regional knowledge to both local and Mutual Aid colleagues in order to support the policing effort of the Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games.
- Provided guidance and thought leadership to external organisations including the Home Office, public safety organisations internationally and private sector.
- Record and promotion of success through a number of case studies, webinars, customer panels and presentations with Google, Samsung &
 VMware.
- Contributed to Forrester TEI for Android Enterprise.

Centre for Applied Automation

- Responsible for the Strategy, Governance and Delivery of the organisations Robotic Process Automation (RPA) capability.
- · Leading a team of developers and requirements consultants to identify, design and deliver automations and performance dashboards.
- Generated and delivered a business case to increase CoE headcount by 300%.
- Designed and oversaw a re-architecture of the solution which delivered significant productivity gains and ROI in excess of 1000%
- Delivered month on month, continual growth with a peak 12 month performance to date of 500,000 transactions, saving 38,000 staff hours, representing £940,000 cost avoidance for the customer, freeing up limited resources to other business critical activities.
- · Coordinating monthly meetings with customer representatives to prioritise activities against strategy to ensure continued success.
- Transition of web chat & chat bot development into the team from 3rd party supplier saving significant external development charges.
- Promotion of customer success through a number of case studies and webinars with the supplier.
- · Contributed to Gartner research.

SELF EMPLOYED

Technology Advisor

Shropshire Aug. 2015 to June 2017

- Providing computing and technology services to residential, charity and SOHO clients.
- Identifying unused licensing and articulating benefits of utilisation of related features.
- Training and advising of various technologies for both purchase and general usage to ensure end-user adoption.
- Managing the online presence of start-up businesses such as maps and business listings & liaising with web developers to arrange web design services.
- Providing computing and research assistance to local charities and working to ensuring their office was digital audit compliant.
- Building, installing, upgrading and maintaining computers, networks and other technologies such as CCTV, AV distribution etc.
- · Installation, configuration and usage training of structured cabling to provide internet, telephone and media distribution.
- Sourcing and managing the installation and programming of an access control system including GSM intercom for a gated community.

GREGG HUDSON

UNIVERSITY OF LEICESTER

Post Doctoral Research Associate

Dec. 2013 to Aug. 2015

Leicester

- · Completion of research project and publication in international journal.
- · Unbiased data handling and analysis & critical review of published literature.
- · Production of publication manuscript.
- Providing discussion of problems and ideas with supervisor and the research group on a regular basis and offering options for solution including instruction on specialized techniques and data analysis.
- Providing technical support and undertaking the upkeep and maintenance of laboratory computers and specialised equipment.
- Work in cross-department panel to provide extensive feedback from the department during the troubleshooting and implementation of a computerised ordering system.
- Training and supervision of BSc, MSc and Ph.D research students.

Leicester, UK; Debrecen, Hungary Sept. 2009 to Oct. 2013

Ph.D Researcher

- Undertaking personal research project investigating protein-protein interactions. Preparation and writing of thesis for PhD submission.
- · Collaborating with other scientists both home and abroad, including a 2-month secondment in a Hungarian laboratory.
- · Providing technical support to colleagues on Windows, UNIX, Macintosh and specialist scientific equipment.
- Providing supervision and guidance for undergraduate and masters project students.
- · Teaching and assessing undergraduate practicals.
- · Providing constructive and critical feedback to students and tutors.
- · Assisting in the modernisation and rewriting of several practical procedures and instructional handbooks.

E.M. DEVELOPMENTS LTD

Derby

Due Diligence Co-Ordinator

Apr. 2007 to Apr. 2007

- Producing comprehensive reports to address the enquiries of the purchasing party during the sale of a contract research organisation.
- Co-ordinating discussion between Directors, Heads of Department and due diligence team to collated the required information for the purchasing parties and their representatives.
- Handling of sensitive and confidential documents.
- · Producing and maintaining detailed computer records for due diligence manager.

ARROWBEAM LIMITED

Birmingham

Data Management Assistant

Summer 2005 to Summer 2005

- Assisting in the transition of shift records from paper documents to a digital, biometrically controlled rostering system for West Midlands Fire Service
- · Handling of sensitive and confidential documents.
- Corresponding with the development team to report bugs discovered in the new platform.

SAFEPHARM LABORATORIES LTD

Shardlow

Computer Services Technician

Summer 2004 to Summer 2007

Summer Holiday Employment - 2004, 2006 & 2007

- Providing desktop support for office and laboratory based staff.
- · Preparation, testing and installation of new computers for users and equipment.
- · Upkeep and maintenance of printers.
- · Installation of Cat5e cabling and termination of sockets.

EDUCATION

University of Leicester

Sept. 2009 to Oct. 2013

Ph.D Biochemistry 2014

University of Leicester

Sept. 2006 to June 2009

BSc (Hons) Medical Biochemistry 2009

AWARDS

Android Enterprise Academy · ANDROID ENTERPRISE EXPERT

June 2022

The highest level of certification, targeted at mobility professionals working with Android in enterprise environments, focusing on technical expertise around implementation, deployment and support.

Assistant Chief Constable (Crime) · AWARD FOR EXCELLENCE IN SERVICE DELIVERY

Nov. 2021

Awarded for my contribution to the delivery of a new Crime Recording Platform that went live in April 2021

Smarter Working Live · AUTOMATION (DIGITAL / ROBOTIC / AI)

Nov. 2020

My Centre for Applied Automation team were the winners in the Automation category at the Smarter Working Live Event run by Gov News Direct and Government Property Agency

Chief Superintendent (Force Contact) · AWARD FOR EXCELLENCE IN SERVICE DELIVERY

Oct. 2020